can't ever idea cafe the mission vision
of the idea cafe is to be a space where
everyone can just show up be who they
are and we can have a fun and hopefully
meaningful conversation around a
question and showcase that everybody has
something to give and hopefully we get
to share in each other's influence a
little bit people get to bring on board
their followers and viewers and we get
to share that amongst amongst other
people as well once we have the video
description I see we actually have some
live viewers too we didn't last week so
everyone's muted at the moment but I'm
gonna ask I'm gonna ask the question and
then whoever wants to go first can just
raise their hands and I will unmute them
and drop everybody else down including
myself so you have the room or the space
I'm the ideas need share for roughly
five minutes I will have a timer on but
share and then I will pop back on when
you have about 30 seconds left so feel
free to wrap up and and finish and I
feel like five minutes is actually a
long time to share for so don't feel
like you need to share until you're done
and then or when I pop on another thirty
seconds okay so this week's question is
what does a beautiful future look like
to you when anyone wants to wants to go
we can just sit with that for a moment
I I guess I'll go okay I'm so awesome
just trying to figure how about the moon
hi i'm ramsey he him i my daughter and I
started common to planet common - planet
org
our beautiful idea is a global reset and
then we would issue a global currency to
each person they would be able to
convert their existing wealth into the
new global currency in addition we could
have a starting balance because most
people don't have any money so it could
be something like say three thousand
times your age so that everybody has
this new currency to start playing the
new game with we could make the currency
issued as a ubi recognizing that each
human has value certainly potential
value and then we could also allow each
person to collect more of this money
through proof of value things like you
know learning playing or working those
are all activities that benefit the
individual and by extension benefit and
produce value for the whole and so and
then of course we can also and this is
the neat part we could also allow
enterprises that is groups of people who
are doing something already
collaboratively together either building
products or service and allow those
enterprises to earn more money based on
metrics other than mere production
things like did they improve their
efficiencies are they producing products
that are renewable reusable recyclable
upgradable etc and so the enterprises in
this game would not necessarily be
competing to outsell one another but
rather to produce the best quality
product or service that is beneficial to
the the whole so then the the trick with
this currency of those unlike money
today this currency once you earn it you
will use it and it will get consumed and
deleted so there is no concern about
creating currency that is producers
property and
circulates and inflates so here's how
that would work so then you have this
currency you go to the grocery store you
go half the food maybe free because
there's plenty and there's no need to
compete for it
the other half you may have to pay for
so when you do pay for it the currency
gets deleted from your account and it
gets deleted and you consume the food
now the money does not have to go to the
enterprise that is the person who
produced it the farmer because what
we're doing here is we're recognizing
that the product was produced from the
Commons right in order for anything to
be produced has to come from the earth
and so none of that can really be owned
by any person at least it shouldn't it
can be controlled by people certainly
and it is but certainly not owned so and
also you have to recall here in this
equation the farmers were already paid
for their labor so they're already
collecting money to produce the the food
they don't need your money on the back
end okay so that's one neat function
there so what that would allow us to do
is it would allow us to make everything
the comments all enterprises all
buildings your entire city would be a
game that we play in terms of inputting
information on what's being used was not
being used
you've got office space that's unused
you would literally you know go on your
application and you can form your own
group whatever it is that you wanted to
pursue could be an engineering could be
you know building something it doesn't
matter you would request lease of the of
the of the office just like you would a
library book for free and then you would
occupy the office for whatever a period
of time that you and your group are
endeavoring towards your purpose and you
would you know essentially create money
for yourself now the beautiful most
beautiful thing about this particular
equation is is that it completely
changes our control of our lives
in that right now you're not allowed to
create value in the world based on your
own morality in your own desire in your
own expertise meaning you have to go out
and accept a position a job from
somebody else in the system you have to
agree to do
something for and obviously we know that
the reason why they want you to do it is
so that they can exploit your labor and
make great value on the back end and
that's ridiculous so here you get to
decide where to work when to work how to
produce value with your you know local
members and global I think that's pretty
much it for now it gets a little bit
more complicated than that and certainly
there is a piece of the property that I
didn't talk about which is the
residential part but the currency part
is the core the concept that allows for
us to basically change the game that we
play in and in this particular economic
equation we can't compete with capitals
meaning we can't Institute through this
game within capitalism because the
currency our game is weaker it is only a
unit of exchange is now property so that
means it deletes so that means we can't
compete against the other currencies
because well once we use ours ours is
gone when they use theirs it just
continues to circulate and never
disappear so anyway so it has to be a
switch that this is why but this is
possible we believe because we have
digital technology so because we can
actually create these accounts for every
single person the plan and the property
portion using an application with the
mapping we can provide these tools for
people and this vision and then give
them an opportunity to help us build it
develop it and maybe one day if we
decide we can switch over to that new
currency and begin playing the whole new
game so that's our additional awesome
thanks Remzi I know you we could talk
about this stuff for hours and we will
see Channel and we will be interviewing
and having a discussion on there thank
you much for sharing I can see the rest
of you you can't necessarily see the
rest everyone else if you want to raise
your hand if you want to be the next
person for sure I will all right awesome
Daniel I'm going to drop Renzi down
Thank You Rosie Daniel Daniel and I'm
gonna drop down and start the Tim okay
sounds great well I love it a lot of
what Wendy was talking about there and
one of the key things that I love is the
piece around changing the game and how
little little changes here and there
changes how all of society and emerges
so for me what a beautiful future looks
like as individualized it's connected
it's fractal and it's diverse and I'll
talk a little bit about what I mean by
those so individualized we have in terms
of Education in terms of lifestyle and
where we live in terms of health in
terms of what we're aiming for in life I
I think we're in a place where there's
room for a lot more individualization
there we have the the technology and
understanding to allow a huge amount of
individualization there
I'll talk maybe more some other time
more dev deeply about that in terms of
connection I think that both being able
to use online distributed connective
tools to connect people to the people
who are sometimes most like them
sometimes people who are on trajectories
that are similar to theirs but maybe a
little bit before a little bit ahead of
where they're at so that there can be
mentorship going on so that we can find
commonality of interests and I'll tell
some diversity and learn from that but
also just in terms of face-to-face
connection I think that we're going
through a period right now societally at
least in Western cultures that's very
isolating for a lot of people and when
we think about individualized it's sort
of every person in their castle very
boxed in very alone often and I think
that we're going to be moving away from
that I think that as we move more
towards understanding where our
happiness and satisfaction comes from
internally that we can start moving more
towards actual connections well with
other other people effectively as well
and what I say fractal I mean that both
of these things that individual is high
utilization and that connectedness piece
is something that rather for being
imposed from on top being all based off
of the equivalent of federal policies or
other outfit than being all some sort of
libertarian individualized way where
each person sort of it's every person
for himself
there can be an iterative process that's
going in both directions and you
have organic patterns kind of appear in
terms of how people are living the
communities they're forming and choosing
the work that's found within there and
then how those communities work together
to make a larger communities there's
already in the Netherlands really
interesting work going on with that
where you'll have cohousing communities
which then have a collective where
multiple cohousing communities come
together and have a larger structure
that they may so I think that's going to
be a king piece I think that part of
that that collaboration and frightful
side helps I couldn't be around decision
making I think we're gonna see a whole
mosaic of different decision making
techniques come in so rather than
current majority rules anonymous vote
democracy which which is made to solve a
whole bunch of problems that are
hundreds of years old I think that we're
gonna find new ways using consensus
using socio cracy using different ways
that are connected and that helped us
come together to find the wisdom of the
group and to then be able to make solid
decisions together and I think they're
connecting the electronic components so
that computers artificial intelligence
can help us with some of that but a lot
of it is about learning communication
skills learning how we talk to one
another how we listen more important
later on another and shifting culture
towards trying to find why this in the
interest of proof when I think I first I
think that a lot of what we're going to
be coming up to and what's what's going
to be marvelous is understanding and
celebrating the importance of that
diversity that when you have monoculture
there's a lot of fragility and brutalist
that's built into that and when you
start to accept that various kinds of
neurodiversity are a strength within the
culture and they bring a whole bunch of
unique elements when you accept that
sexual orientation and identity that
having having the whole spectrum of
what's there be something that's
acknowledged and accepted and celebrated
on that there's huge strength that comes
out of that on peoples culture and their
heritage their unique meaning to their
unique gifts the more those things can
be brought out and again celebrated in
terms of that uniqueness the more we can
then work with each of those different
pieces to build something interesting
and emergent that comes from it
change is going to keep on coming faster
and faster and we're gonna have to learn
how to be responsive to that and I think
that the more were able to to build in
some of these systems make things robust
in terms of how we find our subjects
from within communicate with each other
and then distribute and collectively
make decisions that's going to be a
large part of what helps us whether the
the increasing speed at which we're
gonna be having to make decisions
those are a few little pieces awesome
Thank You Dino I'm sure and turn phones
beep at us in in two seconds all right
would like to go next all right Atlanta
we say goodbye to Daniel thank you so
much Danny I cannot figure out how to
remove people all right let me to
actually ask you the question what does
a beautiful future look like to you
you
okay good I kept trying to indeed myself
but yeah probably worth doing at the
same time hi everyone my name is Lana
and a lot of three years I've been
working with people recovering from
different abuse and trauma and healing
emotionally and yeah it's something that
I've experienced myself and I'm getting
more and more aware how how little we
really know about emotions and emotional
side of life and people and our
humaneness and mmm the beautiful future
looks to me where we are all way more
connected with emotions we're aware of
them and we're able to recognize
different emotional states and people
and children especially and allow space
for that and create more space for
polarities create more space for
different viewpoints perspectives and
experiences as well meaning that if I'm
feeling happy it doesn't mean you have
to feel happy with me right now as well
you can't be sad and we can still hang
out and this is what I've been working
with and helping people to connect with
their emotions to learn about them and
to feel that what we experience and how
we came here I believe is very very
emotional beings and it's kind of at the
core of our existence and educating
people about emotions educating children
as well especially I think that's when I
think parenting and general like
societal structures kind of overlooked
that aspect of life because it's not
oftentimes mission mentioned in the
books at school or parenting books as
well right now of course it's getting a
lot better a lot better and the way I'm
hoping to see us as a humanity
developing in the future that we're not
only paying attention to intelligence
and you know books Mars but we're also
educating ourselves emotionally yeah
that's I think my main thing that I
wanted to share and it's a huge huge
part of my life and she's part of
learning for me at the moment thank you
thank you Lana
that was that was beautiful I'm going to
just review from all right
Nathaniel would you like to would you
like to share if not I can I can share
yeah I certainly can and I hope that my
audio isn't too bad sometimes this
microphone doesn't like to play along
with stream yard first off the things
that heard so far from these amazing
individuals who I have never had the
opportunity to speak with before is
phenomenal and I think all of you for
really considering these things and
actually being empathetic and humanistic
and looking toward the future it means a
lot even if we only more often than not
look at ourselves in the current
perspective and are in our current
situation so looking toward the future
means a lot and to me the future
actually begins today and that's a big
deal I'm down here in Texas and actually
running for public office and for me the
future matters because the future it has
to do with every single person in every
single situation that they're in and
down here that has to do with with with
things that are very intricate things
that have to do with education the
things that have to do with the
beautiful future for me is when a
student can go to a school and be safe
on their way to school and also safe in
their school and at the same time
receive education that's proper
education education that's not
whitewashed and to be able to make them
so they are able to understand basic
intricacies of history but also be able
to perform Admiral II moving forward and
making the
for the proper decisions not based upon
somebody's political ideology in school
but rather upon an accurate
understanding of what's happened and
that to me is beautiful because a person
will be able to to create for themselves
and for others instead of being told
what something was and that begins today
a beautiful future for me is when every
single student in every single all 5.5
million Texas public school students and
also the millions and millions of
students across the United States of
America are are given an opportunity to
understand what sex education actually
is because we have an issue in the
United States with maternal mortality
rates we have an issue with ST is we
have an issue with teenage pregnancies
maternal mortality rates and we have an
issue in the United States with all of
this having to come down to this idea of
morality a beautiful future for me is
telling people that sexuality is normal
and if we're going to engage in
sexuality then we need to understand
what it is and for me that's beautiful
because sexuality is beautiful being
able to provide for each other to me is
beautiful the way we can do that in all
these other ways looking to other
countries from the United States
perspective and looking to what has been
put in place for health care and what
has been put in place for income basic
income or otherwise and how we can lift
ourselves above what we currently are
and give each other the opportunity to
succeed
the success of all matters more than the
success of a few and for me there's so
much that goes into it and and and
you're right when you say that you could
talk about this for hours you've seen me
do it before I've laid out things that I
want to see starting today things that
that that are important tomorrow because
we focus on them today
and and I love your videos that you've
done where you spoken about so well we
can see the next 10 years and I really
do and I don't give you enough enough
credit for them because they are very
forward-looking
and for me I believe that that starts
right now in the decisions that we make
today and I think that when we hear
ideas like this they sound so you know
alien to us but I think that's a good
thing as well a beautiful feature to me
is beginning to listen to these things
having to do with emotional positivity
having to do with what we're doing the
global currency having to do with how
we're going to remove nuclear weapons
from the world nothing is more beautiful
than understanding that nobody has nukes
and seeing how we're going to help each
other and lift each other up to me is
beautiful and the way we were able to do
that and I think this is part of that
and so I thank you for that - that was
perfect that was like 30 seconds to go I
was gonna pop in in like three seconds
all right and I'm just going to drop you
down and then I'll share a my my answer
I can figure this out all right thank
you everyone for sharing this is my
beautiful future having a space for
everyone to be able to come to and share
who they are and have humanity fall in
love with one another to see who I know
we're more connected and divided I can
see the genius and amazingness in every
single human being and we create the
tools that allow us to live that life
when we have our needs met our food
needs and our shelter needs and we have
the tools to connect with real people
and we have all of these amazing
products that Remzi and Daniel and Lana
and Nathaniel when they get to live
their life when they get to have the
space to help people in the way that
they want to help people that is my idea
of a beautiful future and I think it is
absolutely possible because I can see
how we do it and a big piece is this the
idea cafe that as we're able to come
together this is a this is broadcast
live on YouTube and hopefully it will
grow but the idea is we're gonna create
our own platform that isn't reliant on
their algorithm that isn't reliant on on
their and I'm just realizing now I did
not start recording my I didn't know
start talking about
but I do have a little clock in the
corner that we have our own platform
that anyone can show up to and have a
conversation with real people around a
question it doesn't need to be broadcast
to the world because I think it does
make it a different forum I'm also
realizing as I can see all the little
pictures down below and people are
nodding along that you all can't see
that and there is something disconnected
in that but like there's there's a
there's a trade-off right now because
we're going live and because we're doing
it in this format that some people who
might want to share aren't gonna feel
comfortable doing it this way and we're
not going to have that same human
connection that we are when we create
our own platform but this is a space and
a way forward to get people together to
say what do we have in common what are
our stories how do we find our
commonality even if we don't agree on a
lot of the things that are dividing us
in this world and so that is my
beautiful future and I thank you all for
coming to helping create it a little bit
I'm gonna add everybody back in I just
want to mention Lana I think your
bangles are I think you might have
bracelets on that we're like right by
your mic when you were talking so maybe
we could do something about that that
would be awesome
I don't know if you for choosing to be
muted you can always choose to be muted
or you can unmute yourselves I won't do
what I did to Lana which we were both
trying to mute and unmute at the same
time ended up you know being a disaster
so now I would like to invite we have
about like five more minutes left the
idea is for this to be half an hour so
there could be another half an hour
after and we can keep although if we
wanted to go over a little bit I know
Remzi has to get to oh yeah there you
are slip denied your back end has to get
to a podcast interview at in a little
bit but to share to share what we got
from listening to each other and what
what is in present in the moment right
now one thing sublime for me and just in
this in listening to each of you because
there's there's a lot of wisdom and neat
ideas and inspiration to them hearing
that's their envision and to me one of
the key parts of a beautiful future
is that feeling of empowerment and for
people to have the space you know have
enough of their Maslow's hierarchy of
needs met have shelter have food have
the ability to figure out what is it
that that I see and that I can be giving
to the world that's unique and that's
the piece that I have I think that the
biggest tragically underutilized
resource that we have is ourselves and
then we have millions of people with
genius ideas and compassion and vision
who are spending their time in jobs that
they don't like stressing out trying to
meet their basic needs and the level of
disconnection and antipathy that we
sometimes get from that whereas if we're
able to just breathe and live and have a
little bit of space all of these kinds
of inspirations can come out so so
that's a big piece for me is how do we
shift our story as individuals and come
to that place of empowerment and where
we can connect with others who mmm thank
you so much for creating this such a
beautiful place and feeling seen and
heard and safe to express and to just
you know share the ideas the thoughts
and yeah I completely agree with you
the way you describe the beautiful
future and what you want and what you
are already creating it's really really
beautiful
thank you I chose to not become as
passionate as you seen me before that
was that that was a personal choice I
can do that if you'd like but I chose
not to because all this does matter to
me every every single thing that's in
here right now I'm not running for
public office because it's fun by the
way people say people say things to me
and about me that are first off untrue
but also are incredibly negative and
even so having things like this where
people say you know what these are our
visions for the future and how we can we
bring this all together and
that each that each person is actually
valued really helps me a lot and it's
kind of nice that I don't have that I
don't have to say hey everybody should
have access to things and not get yelled
at so I think for me that too is the
most inspiring thing of all this is that
so many of us have the desire and this
vision of a more inclusive collaborative
world and so it's it's refreshing to
know that we're not alone and that the
majority that people actually want the
same thing that we do and so I find that
incredibly inspiring you know and I just
want to say the final kudos for going
into that realm of public office that
said that's a hard place to be and
especially when you're someone who is
seeking connection going into a place
that is so about polarization and
looking at how can i how can I slice
this person down using the most sort of
strong man arguments as possible and I
think that's going to be another thing
that's gonna be really exciting watching
change is how we deal with political
discourse and how we get involved so the
people don't simply get involved in a
giant slug fest but ever election time
comes but having a sense of what civic
responsibilities means is being actively
constantly engaged and how how do we do
things locally in our in our communities
in our society that make things better
and engage with people of different
viewpoints in a way that is humanized
the corgis are barking in the background
I apologize for that I I completely
agree with you and while I plan on on on
replacing my opponent next next November
I also have an incredible amount of
respect for anybody that's willing to do
something like this and I've actually
attempted to reach out to him he's never
responded to any of my requests to
actually sit down and talk to him but to
actually to do something like this to
where because all of us have a vision
for the future regardless of what it is
and that's the reason we do things like
this well the reason we were in public
office right and or whatever we do
whatever venture
we that we that we go that we start and
we go out into and for me it's I
mentioned the things that I have and and
Jubilee has seen and heard me speak
about some of my platforms and when I
got on to Austin it's not - it's not to
be a politician but rather to be a
person who is working for people and and
I've had people ask me what about money
and things like that and people actually
offered to give me money from businesses
and stuff like that and I turned them
down because businesses aren't people
and I working with people and seeing the
pleading in people's eyes for basic
health care and basic education to die
I've cried with people because they they
said for the first time in 74 years they
think that they can actually have access
to health care it's very very emotional
especially down here and so seeing that
is and listening to each of you as well
how there's a unique way to be able to
address these very unique opportunities
that we have that we have before us
really gives me opportunity to consider
things as well even in Texas where
people say I can't win
I mean I'm gonna by the way and and
really he thank each of you very very
much you all matter to me and even
though you can't vote for me you all
matter to me very much and I said I say
that knowing you can't vote for me so
that guys you know I know it's real
gotta be real so we're at the little
past the half an hour mark so we're
gonna wrap this up thank you so much for
joining us I want to say that this is
not my space this is our space so if
like Nathaniel you wanted to hold an
idea cafe with people in Texas to ask
about and have them share their idea for
a future whatever we can generate new
questions the idea is just to showcase a
conversation around a question and I
could sit there and just put pot people
up I don't even need to be on screen
because I need to share my vision for
Texas and you know Remzi if you want to
to do one on your idea of the future
it's annular Lana with with what you're
working on the idea is to create a space
to showcase how powerful a conversation
in connection will be if anybody
watching this live or in replay would
like to participate you can participate
live by getting in touch with me or you
could also just upload a five-minute
video sharing your answer to this week's
question post the link in the comments
or post it on the Facebook group and
together we are going to create a world
of connection we are going to create the
actual platform that we are gonna
co-owned and and run together that
connects us in a way that no existing
social media is going to because it's
not run for us it's run for profit and
so thank you all for for joining and I'm
gonna put the links of the links to all
these amazing people in the description
later today so that you can find them if
you want to get in contact with them so
thank you everyone and see some of you
next week just happen every week bye
thanks Julie like hi let's meet you guys
good beaches mom